

Tomás Arroyo

Data Scientist · Data Engineer · Data Analyst.

<u>Linkedin</u> Github

tomasarroyomzk@icloud.com

Data Scientist with a background in Education and Music Production, which has enhanced my communication skills, interpersonal relationships, and the ability to carry out individual and group projects. Proficient in agile methodologies, workflow processes, data structure, and evaluation of machine learning models. Experienced in data architecture, analysis and report generation. I am a self-taught, curious, empathetic, and creative human. Advanced level in English.

Skills: Python, Tableau, Power Bi, SQL, Hadoop, Spark, AWS, Docker, Javascript, Git, Office, Linux, Adobe.

PROJECTS

Data Scientist "Machine Learning Operations"

Developed a Machine Learning model to recommend games to Steam platform users based on their previous experiences. The model was integrated into an API and deployed on the web.

- Data collection and transformation
- Machine Learning model creation
- Model deployment.

Tools: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Render. <u>DEPLOY</u> <u>REPOSITORY</u>

Data Analyst - "Airplane Accidents"

Served as a data analyst for the International Civil Aviation Organization, analyzing historical data on airplane accidents since the early 20th century to understand variations over time, mortality rates, survival rates, geolocations, and involved airlines.

- Data extraction, transformation, and cleaning.
- exploratory data analysis (EDA),
- KPI'S proposition, measurement, and visualization.
- interactive dashboards for data understanding.

Tools: Python, Pandas, Numpy, Seaborn, Matplotlib. REPOSITORY

Data Engineer "New York Cabs"

Integral project focused on understanding the relationship between environmental impact and the profitability of the taxi market in new york, and determining if it is still a profitable business nowadays. REPOSITORY

- ETL
- dashboard
- machine learning calculator.

Tools: Jira, Streamlit, PowerBi.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Audiovisual Producer - Communicator (National Electoral Chamber, Buenos Aires, Argentina, Feb 2018-2020)

 Managed communication channels, created audiovisual content (photography, videos, animations), and monitored live audio for events.

Electoral Debate Organization 2019 (National Electoral Chamber, Buenos Aires, Argentina, Oct - Dec 2019)

Planned and managed organization.

Administrative (Arroyo and Associates Engineering Firm, Entre Ríos, Argentina, 2020-Present)

Budgeting, paying suppliers, invoicing clients, documenting, and tracking project progress.

Wakeboard Instructor (Club Nautico Paraná, Entre Rios, Argentina, Feb 2018-2020)

Teaching and pedagogy applied to sports, group leadership.

Music Teacher (Feb 2018-Present)

• Teaching and pedagogy applied to art, instruction in instruments such as piano and guitar, as well as musical theory and audio perception.

Music Producer (Feb 2013-Present)

Recording, editing, mixing, and mastering songs.

Education

- Data Science: Henry Bootcamp, 700 hours of theoretical-practical course, 2023.
- B.A. in Psychology, 2020.
- Python Codo a Codo 4.0, 2022.
- Javascript Programming Course, Plataforma 5, 2021.
- Professional Musician, Buenos Aires School of Music, 2015.
- Audio and Digital Sound Editing Course, UTN regional Paraná, 2013.

Languages

• English: C2 - Advanced

• Portuguese: Basic